welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where equal hear and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
welcome to the stoah peter lindbergh the
steward of the stoah stoah as a place
for us to go here and dialogue about
what matters most edge of this moment
and today we have Pat Ryan in the dark
stoah the most dangerous man on the
internet who's waving quite friendly
right now and so this is a season 2 of
mantling humanism I think that's that's
the title of it so you know the drill if
you've been here before if you haven't
Pat's been to talk if you have a
question put in the chat box I will call
on you and then you want mute yourself
if you want me to read your question
your behalf just let me know and I'll be
down your bath that being said I will
hand it over to you Pat and you need to
have your screen hold on should work now
thanks son hello folks welcome back for
round 2 of season 2 which is devouring
humanism which is a play on words when
you think about it typically I tend to
give a talk about what it is you're
gonna face so I'll do that this one is
called absurd logic and the previous
video I approached the blue church from
a Gallion Marxist dialectic the ability
to dismantle using critical theory
against the structure all of the parts
in which it was made up of and how to
inverse every advantage it had and how
to describe how to how to inverse every
advantage of had and how to take
everything that it penalized you for and
turned that into a benefit now I'm not
going to use Marxist dialectic in every
aspect of the blue church when I
criticize it because I loathe that so
much I'm going to throw multiple
critical theories at it so this one is
going to be dedicated to alchemy which
is going to be the inverse of logic and
using alchemical review as a way to
ah make systemic abuse go away and this
particular one's going to be the last
one focused on the last one focused on
the identity heuristics that the blue
church tends to favor and how to tear
those apart how to break them down how
to invert them this one were going to be
focusing on the types of logic that the
blue church tends to promote and the
types of logic that in umber slee then
denies and pretends doesn't exist so
without further ado let us start okay so
served logic I think two dates right
what's wrong whatever okay so season one
is we're still exploring this meme this
was season one Gnostic warfare for those
who are new season two is devouring
humanism as I said in Episode two is
going to focus on these parts of the
meme so it's gonna focus on the saying
terrorism it's like car accidents ergo
you have to wear a seatbelt at all times
because you never know when the
terrorism happens Liberty versus safety
which is a trap that people in the blue
church constantly find themselves in and
are unable to resolve and that's on
purpose sciencism which is the idea of
being science advocates over being
scientists it's funny how the two tend
to blend together orthogonality which
means trying to represent multiple
features of a system without them
technically overlapping but there's a
lot more to that and this is actually a
critical part of the blue church and
we're gonna examine why that's the case
functional AI meaning AI that doesn't do
analysis it's the type of AI that just
comes up with a conclusion and then acts
on it and it's effectively not liable
for its actions as we see in things like
you know social media and Twitter and
Google pattern recognition taboo meaning
you see a pattern prepare to get slapped
for it if it's outside of the church's
domain utilitarianism which we're gonna
go all into centralizing the imbecilic
imbecility
of subsystems which means if you take a
complex machine and you break it down
into subsystems you make those
subsystems intentionally simple to
control even if they are dispersed with
one another you can add this like
centralization layer on top of these
subsystems without actually having to
get within the machine and this is a
core part of how the blue church
infiltrates and takes over everything it
touches
so we'll be exploring all of this
hilarious nests let's start with
orthogonally which is the first and
final oppressor of mankind that's a
weird thing to say but I promised Alex
I'll get to it we'll start with the L
which is an ancient name for the cubit
the cubit was a very old way of
measuring wealth so if you had stacks of
cloth or stacks of gold or whichever you
would use cubits to determine how much
your trade was going to be especially on
the Silk Road in antiquity now the thing
about trying to measure how much gold is
worth how much silk is worth how much
cotton is that you don't necessarily
have an international standard to for
metrics at this time in the Bronze Age
the Chinese have one metric the Middle
East as another Europe has another how
do you bring it all together it's uh
it's not easy to say you know my cubits
more cubit than your cubit and that's
that's just an endless argument so what
they did is they started looking at
their own bodies and they said well you
know what
no that's the spot between my elbow my
finger that's pretty much the same
everywhere we go in the world so we'll
just use that and this became the
standard in which you measured your
trade in you would you would measure you
know how how many lengths between my
elbow and my finger were we actually
trading here and this was as close as
you could get as at a universal metric
system to conduct trade in a fair manner
across systems which had totally
incompatible metric systems between one
another and it plus it was intuitive and
it was hard to skimp on you know he
couldn't just like grow your arm wasn't
actually a thing he could do so this was
a this
it's worked for a long time of course
the cubit which is you'll see actually
in the biblical and Bible as well being
mentioned there and something
interesting about this is that in
addition to this being the the source of
accounting this counting naturally leads
to mathematics in fact that bone is
called the radius and you know these two
things we start to see that okay there's
a variableness between the humerus and
the radius now it looks like that oh my
god we just figured out some basic
geometry using our arm and we're
incentivized to do so because we're
already using this part of our arm for
trade so now we start to see that
there's a relationship between these
lines because we're just doing all of
our trade here all the time anyway and
it's a reason that bone the radius is
the radius here in mathematics as well
this is the origin of the etymology or
watching the origin of mathematics being
born see the radius is right there now
where do we get the orthogonal stuff
this is very you know the radius could
be anywhere in the circle but just like
the arm could be anywhere within reason
it's not like I can bend it this way and
break myself but for the most part the
idea that it was adjustable was a
concept so where do we get two
orthogonal means where do we get two
intersecting lines or or right angles
well again put ourselves in
psychohistory getting a straight line in
antiquity is almost impossible there's
actually no way you a human being can
create a straight line in a way that's
reduplicate bull because there's gonna
be tiny variations it's gonna be
mistakes if I try to make this line on a
horizontal surface and I try to make it
on any one of these points I'm gonna be
wrong and then when you're trying to
measure stuff based on that if your
measurements are off then everything you
do from there is off to so how do you
actually get a straight line given the
severe limitations you have during the
Bronze Age we have what's called the
plumb line this is an old ancient
technique that's still used today to
figure out the straightness of whatever
it is you're trying to do in terms of
architecture in particular so how do we
know this is a straight line well it's
because of gravity if we tie a
heavyweight to this rope
get a straight line the only straight
line we can actually form in nature in
antiquity so we can actually create we
took this Platonic ideal of mathematics
and we can actually create it in the
real world we have a we have this
mathematic ideal represented using this
technique known as the plumb line
now from this plumb line I can then
figure out okay how straight how level
am I am I being level we see this right
now and like well not leveling it's a
different story but but this plumb line
is a way to determine okay is anything
off here if this was tilted this way
then I wouldn't have the parallel that
I'm looking for so my building will
collapse if these aren't parallel so I
can very tightly carefully measure each
brick as I go along the line and make
sure that I'm paralyzed with this
reproducible constant that I can throw
everywhere I need to throw it down this
is incredibly useful and still used to
this day in construction in fact this
was so useful that very old
civilizations and modern ones used it as
well and you'll see this that's the
plumb line as well this is the point of
reference in which you can do additional
mathematics you can actually figure out
ok how far is the star from where I'm at
the Patek could figure this out just
from the plumb line alone and then
you'll see in the medieval periods
trying to measure how tall building is
from the plumb line alone so this is a
this is where we actually cross the
ideals of mathematics and bring them
into realities from this part alone and
this is an orthogonal line by default
this is why this line exists we're
trying to create
orthogonality between the ground and
gravity itself so you have all of
civilization from one line it's crazy
it's crazy to think about that but
that's that's absolutely the case it's
one line and then furthermore about why
the arm is used humans are pretty good
at watching each other and observing
each other and when they're trying to
figure out this problem of of measuring
how to conduct trade and make sure it's
fair but they looked at all parts of
their body they didn't just pick the
radius because they it's bored one day
and they said hey that's a good part of
the body
use it turns out when you measure the
average distance differences between
bodies and body links at the same age
the radius is the least variation of the
average so if you use the tibia the
fibula or the humerus you have a greater
variation of the average and so you'd
have more unfair trade the radius was
actually the most stable out of all the
bones and or I should say the least
variation of average between human
beings and different cultures and
everything else so you have this
intuitive and reliable heuristic the
standardized value in a world full of
relative value assessment so it's like a
hack and it's like a great like unifier
of trade which is great and again you
know all these different empires that
their own different interpretations of
mathematics and trade using your arm is
you know not bad so so when the world
ends and you got to restart trade you
got your arm you're ready to go you can
do it I believe in you so now because we
can measure stuff and we could bring the
ideals of mathematics into the real
world and get real-world results let's
just go all the way with it let's you
know we can build buildings let's try to
measure happiness now we you know it's
just nope think big that's right Jeremy
Bentham comes in this guy use utility uu
utilitarianism is usually utility i'ma
call him utility men because I don't
like him
so social reformer there's a pile of
buzzwords coming up right so fundamental
axiom this is a person who thought
trying to find that that one plumb line
for all of society that one line that
you can then extrapolate all other
possibilities from he was a plumb line
seeker for sure it's the greatest
happiness of the greatest number that is
the measure of right and wrong oh boy we
may be starting hitting problems for
some people in the audience and other
people be like I don't see your problem
with this well hang tight I'm gonna do
my best to make it funny to explain why
this could probably spiral out of
control if you're not careful so you
know political radical which I always
love that word radical I call like
kitten's radical and like not calling
humans radical because it pisses him off
a political radical of ideals influenced
the development of welfarism that sounds
familiar
individual economic freedoms sure
churches say freedom of expression equal
rights for women right the divorce this
guy is freaking progressive he's ready
to go to criminalizing homosexual acts
head of his time look at him go
abolition of slavery capital punishment
physical punishment including that of
children this guy just he doesn't want
humans he wants humans to be happy right
but these are all of the things he can
do from the legal standpoint to get
people happy she's all I cared about
he's he's just like one of those people
pleasers I mean he just turned it into a
political thing edible rights no natural
rights he was very skeptical the idea of
a natural law and natural rights
god-given nonsense up on stilts he
caught it in exact wording so this guy
is just like a literal blue charge
saying you should just tell like if you
like the blue church there's a tattoo
this guy to your face it's pretty solid
like this is it you'll never beat this
guy right except the problem where he
invented the pan off the con so so
whoops right so in addition to making
sure that people reach this happiness
his idea was to make the perfect prison
and there's a well that's just that's a
juxtaposition if you really kind of
think about that so like you know making
sure that in order for prisoners to
reform them to make them happier or to
fit them in a crowd of people which are
happy and the prisoner might not be you
used to pan off the contact neke which
is you have this this this observation
deck in the center which should be
blacked out you shouldn't be able to see
whether someone's inner but then all the
prisoners are looking at it because
their cells are facing inward and
because they don't know if a guard is in
the cell or not the guard is now for the
prisoners now forced to modify their own
behavior so I don't have to actually put
a gun or a prod or you know make fun of
them they just assume the guards
watching them even if there is none and
and all of you have lived in you're
currently living in this world today if
you've ever walked into a convenience
store and you see a security camera but
it's like this really shaded glass you
don't know if the cameras looking at you
or not
well congratulations this guy invented
that so he invented this cot this Big
Brother the eye is watching you even if
the eyes not there the all-seeing eye
yeah it's this guy your blue church
who was all about making happiness hey
only way you could do is by putting you
in prison look at that so we're already
jumping the shark right we didn't have
to go very far to to realize that maybe
this concept has some problems and then
we have John Stuart Mill who is an
intellectual Titan for sure the guy
wrote extensively and I'm gonna cherry
pick and I'm gonna admit my bias here
I'm cherry picking here feel free to
attack me appropriately this guy was
probably the closest to an actual
political philosopher Britain has ever
independently developed very very
influential stuff but he was again he
was one of those utility guys saying
that pleasure itself reality utility is
to find his pleasure itself and the
absence of pain straight up right no
bones about it no actions are right in
proportion that they tend to promote
happiness and tend is a good good
defensive word for to be used there
that's it's clever as smart wrong as a
tend to produce the reverse of happiness
buy happiness is intended pleasure and
the absence of pain and buy unhappiness
pain and the privation of pleasure
meaning happiness is when you can get
pleasure and there is no pain and
unhappiness is when there is pain and
you do not get pleasure actions are good
lead to a higher general level of
happiness and bad would need to crease
that level so this may sound novel and
interesting and free license to to to
say fuck you dad forever but this isn't
new this is old stuff
it's called hedonism Greeks invented dis
ages ago
he just stole it so he did he gave it a
fancy name at a time when people were
developing access to world well
humongous amounts of capital and they
couldn't be confined under a king so
this type of ideology really appeals to
that type of people who say well
colonies are overthrowing their masters
all the time and there's Wars and we
don't need monarchs or churches we have
our own money we're good thanks this is
the ideology of those people that's all
that's all it was
and again the hedonism which you know
ethical hedonist would defend that
either increasing pleasure and reducing
suffering of all beings capable of
experiencing them and that's what we
should and that's basically what we
should be doing you know he's a person
who invented it was a student Socrates
hailed the idea that pleasure is the
highest good and this is John Stuart
Mill just for this segment of his work
here's a whole body of work beyond this
segment but for this segment it's just
hedonism always doing is promoting
hedonism that's it and again
another blue church state saint of the
highest order and this is true in
Britain and in America
so here's what our there's your hedonism
folks ideal utility just heroin up you
know don't need to do anything else we
got the SOB thank you john stuart mill
so i'm gonna focus my criticism has been
flippant so far so i'm gonna focus on a
very specific part of it i'm gonna focus
on that word right there now you might
say pat come on you're just splitting
hairs how are you gonna focus on a word
to take down a comprehensive philosopher
who really really got it right like how
do you how how can you even do that and
here's how i can do that because level
implies measuring happiness right yeah
the idea that we can put a number i have
seven Happy's and tomorrow i have nine
Happy's right so we're putting this
level on it and why is this a problem
well again the criticisms fair yes me
fixating on a single word might be out
of order but bear with me i'm not the
first to do this let's look at fellows
cific calculus that was a thing so like
john Daria's jeremy bentham once again
coming up with an attempt to force fuck
mathematics to comport to this idea of
measuring happiness they believed the
new moral rightness and wrongness of an
action to be a function of the amount of
pleasure or pain that is a function
right a mathematical function a
transformation of inputs to outputs as
utility calculus he missed a calculus
this type of thing here's all the things
you know the duration and certainty and
all the all the arbitrary factors that
he put into this calculate or e method
so basically that's forces the
association of pleasure and pain as an
orthogonal and I'll give you a
demonstration of that because it's not
enough to simply say that that pain is
over here and pleasure is over here
that's not enough it's actually
orthogonal and I'll get into that and
then exploit that mathematical Authority
because it's math of course math is if
you find anything in map and it's always
true for ever and ever right and we're
gonna turn pleasure-seeking into a
full-blown political system that's where
it ends so look at that
back here again Wow kind of strange it's
your peak utility once again if heroin
isn't enough call Epstein he'll up yep
okay so here's that orthogonality I was
talking about so this is much joy very
pleased small join join should be join
tiny pleased small pain tiny ouch much
pain very out right so real bad a lot of
pain not a lot of pain really a lot of
pleasure not a lot of pleasure right so
here's your orthogonality because again
you can't just simply say pain is the
absence of pleasure it's very possible
to experience both at the same time if
you're into that stuff it's also very
positive it's also you know if you have
not a lot of pleasure and not a lot of
pain you're probably asleep you know
that's a reality too so things happen
right so it's orthogonal and this this
right here is the line this is the plumb
line of the blue church
right so this is the plumb line that
once I can establish it I can build the
entirety of the right side of history
narrative because I am getting I'm
maximizing pleasure and I am reducing
pain and that is my moral authority and
from that plumb line I can extract the
entirety of everything afterwards so
again it's called a blue church and
there's a reason for that
once you from a line you can create
shapes from shapes you can make symbols
and from symbols you can make churches
so from this line I will be able to show
you how to build a blue Church of your
own oh and by the way and if you're
outside of that line you're your North
Sea which I can't say anymore because
you know everyone's listening so if
you're if you don't like pain or
pleasure you're still ignored see if you
if you like a lot of pain and no joy
you're a Protestant and satanic Nazis
are apparently a thing now so you know
just keep the hits coming but you're
supposed to stay here right this is
where you're gonna be and there's a
whole medley of reasons why you're
forced here even against your will just
like that Bentham prison where we're
gonna measure that happiness and
goddamnit we're gonna keep you here so
let's start with how a civilization kind
of appears at a high level heuristic
start with linguistics just people
talking gratulations
we're talking awesome we're green we're
not being violent we're talking so
that's a start we can probably build
from there further so we get a you know
we figure out political things just just
a block button nowadays but we figure
out political stuff cultural studies
education we start to grow this
linguistic capacity into these other
ways of trying to figure out how to
manage ourselves as our populations grow
and as our experiences with nature grows
education and linguistics naturally lead
to philosophy philosophy leads and
mathematics and the political process
and cultural studies lead the geography
because this is how you allocate your
collective resources to claim land and
have a base and a presence in these type
of things meanwhile mathematics is over
here just fucking off from philosophy
Shen leaves the Natural Sciences
geography then leads to economics and
these lines flow back into each other by
the way I should have pointed that out
so it's not like linguistics leads a
political process political process can
also influence
linguistics it's all back-and-forth
everything can influence everything here
an attention relationship to economics
is a byproduct of geography as multiple
actors upon the geographic sphere are
now forced to use their arms to trade
with one another natural natural
sciences comes from mathematics finance
as a result of economics this poor guy
he just can't print fast enough gotta
measure all that money in the debt and
all that stuff that leads to the trades
people were building stuff before all of
this complicated thing yeah that's true
but in terms of like properly
configurating and deploying labor in a
way that was profitable you needed all
this stuff in place first so you get to
the trades and as like this like this
vehicle this function of civilization
that comes roughly after finance
surprisingly because the people were
trading regardless but this actually
organized them as a fist then you have
material sciences as the trades interact
with the earth and find more stuff about
nature they have questions and you want
better things about the earth like I
find some dirt now what if I apply fire
to it oh I get no hardened clay and I
can do stuff so these two things work
together to actually generate material
sciences and once we get here once we
cross this rubric or a Rubicon we
stumble upon this mess we get here and
once we figure this one out this is
where the blue church line kinda comes
from trying to figure out okay
there's humans in this system how do i
optimize for each one how do i make them
better
how do i increase pleasure and reduce
pain
now it infects linguistics first we're
going to increase the pleasure of
linguistics and reduce the pain of
linguistics we're gonna say there's
certain words you're allowed to say in
certain words you're not allowed to say
and then we're gonna constantly change
up the definition of things too so you
never really know what's going on and
once we're successfully able to put a
blue plumb line there well then we could
spread out then we can do the same thing
to the political process how do we
maximize the pleasure of the political
process and minimize the pain well we're
gonna make sure you only vote for things
that are good for you who cares who else
gets affected it's your pain and your
pleasure that matters so we're gonna
make that to normal now for cultural
studies we want to increase the pleasure
and reduce the pain how do we do that
well there's certain there's certain
cultures that we want to focus on and if
certain cultures we're not gonna focus
on because it's painful we're not gonna
focus on the horrible truth of slavery
we're gonna focus on some some abstract
representation of it some scapegoat
version of it but we're not gonna focus
on the real thing cuz if we did that
we'd be there all day so we're gonna
maximize the pleasure and not talk about
that shit then we're gonna do the same
thing to psychology and education and
philosophy and before you know it it
doesn't get here yet you'd think it
would go here but we saved this one for
last cuz you got to get the whole of
civilization before he can actually
change it to you the geography of it so
now we got to go from mathematics we've
already targeted philosophy we've
already got you to the utility guys in
control of philosophy here great now
we're gonna do math now we're coming to
the realm of absurd logic where we're
selecting for math that makes us more
pleasurable and math that creat that
crease that drives pain throw it out the
window so it's not enough to say well
I'm logical so I win that's not
sufficient the fact is there are plenty
of logical conclusions in mathematics
that are not the highlight or focus of
any type of serious research only the
ones that have been selected are those
that have followed this blue line this
plumb line mathematics that increase the
concept of pleasure and decrease pain I
think the most wonder the most obvious
one that comes to mind
I would say
let's take relativity for example
relativity has all kinds of fun
terminology and concepts associated with
it that are directly built somehow on
all of these other pre-cut herb Lew
Church plumb lines the idea that oh
there is no fixed points there's no
fixed morality there's no fixed universe
there's only everything in relation to
each other well you can come to that
conclusion as long as you can pre
subvert all of these other effects of
civilization because then when this guy
makes its claim and says ah well we
could take relativity and say yeah
here's some actual math behind it that
works but then we're gonna create a
sciencism culture about relativity and
we're gonna use that as a narrative to
to reinforce that everything's relative
man lay back and chill what are you
doing so that we'd push that to the
Natural Sciences let me push it the
material then we push it to the trades
before you know it you have finance with
Goldman Sachs out there running around
caring about what the LBG LGBT flag all
of a sudden like where were they 30
years ago right there's economics and
then finally you get the geography so
this is how a blue church infiltrates an
entire civilization by simply selecting
for what's pleasurable and preventing
what's painful it's all it has to do
let's see it's not this complicated
conspiracy it's not like moo-ha-ha the
top of the throne room and smoky cigar
rooms it's a simple selection criteria
you infiltrate a group and you simply
say does this cause pleasure no get out
yes you win all you have to do is define
what pleasure is of course but then you
got to stick to your guns and it's easy
to do because well everybody wants
pleasure it's like it's like arguing for
the for the lowest IQ least Age person
in the entirety of civilization using
that as your foundation which is why
this shit works all the time so this is
how this is a blue church just
infiltrates everything they use they use
pleasure that's it
device no magic trick no nothing
so now once they start infiltrating
signs with this technique they there is
a fun side effect where they can
actually conflate science to moral
authority so you could say well
mathematics isn't biased and science
isn't biased we have a whole team of
people who aren't princes and kings and
and people who aren't in the political
process they're just scientists are
observing nature and it's important to
make sure that we bind our behavior to
what we know about nature and we
synchronize them at all times
because that's how we can get a moral
authority that isn't corruptible because
I can't Crump an atom I mean what's the
point of Bitcoin I can't corrupt a
a-minor I can't I can't go in there and
say hey minor you're gonna you got a
Bitcoin process extra for like for like
libertarians and instead of monarchists
right you can't really do that so
there's there's an because of that
corruption factor that exists in every
part of the political process you do
want to select this authority that's
outside of it and so Science and
Mathematics is usually the first
candidate however if you put that blue
line in science you get the veneer of
moral authority without having to
acknowledge that you're actually have
subverted it here's what that looks like
so a question pops up and say why do we
starve to death
okay so some scientists answer and it's
just a wall of crap that happens bro I'm
not reading that shit like I'm starving
I'm not reading that oh but here's some
good propaganda now this face I just saw
this I'm like that's not natural I know
that that's a photoshopped like that is
an engineered face to make you look at
it and go what like look at that there's
like dodge around the eyes I don't think
that those eyes even belong to that like
subset of people those lips are like 20
years older than issue this is like an
engineered face designed for people to
go oh right this is like this is like
psycho weapon the face right so why do
we start there oh this person said and
they have an excuse oh it's because
because the people who made you star if
they wanted to kill ideas and beauty
quality piece and man so now had this
moral champion running around and then
you have this block of text which
actually has the answer in here
somewhere in this mess is probably a
pretty damn good argument of why you
actually starved good
been a crop storm or global warming or
whatever is probably good answer in here
but but this is what actually works now
why does this work well that here's the
two people user who's our scientists who
double as moral authorities who don't
know it of course then they pretend to
not know it and here's why they're all
liars because they made this piece they
turned this motherfucker out and they're
right yeah but this is the audience
man they hate words have you seen these
people they hate where words hurt them
like it like it hurt like physically
causes pain to them to see words but
they listen to the sad girl oh so sad so
now the the whims of the people they
don't care about this they care about
this so how do I increase my public
funding well I care about that tada
so now you had these these supposedly
impartial scientists and their moral
authority well now they're just populist
populist opportunists that's it so
they're no longer outside of the
political process they are part of the
political process
they are the political process
effectively this of course leads to
pattern recognition problems so there's
only certain people who are allowed to
see patterns and everyone else is not
authorized to see the pattern you're not
allowed to see the pattern only
scientists are allowed to see the
pattern the rest of your conspiracy
theorists here's what that looks like
right side of history has some opinions
says for maximum happiness because
that's what we're doing we're increasing
maximum happiness we've forced racial
integration not for most people that's
probably like all right that's a good
thing yeah that is a good thing I mean
aside for the fact that it totally
destroyed black communities and their
ability to be economically you know
robust aside from that then yeah it was
great No it gave cheap labor to Ford
gave cheap labor for the entire north
yeah I made a lot of money off that
fantastic right so super good then you
say four maxima happy and maximum
happiness you got to put that first you
got to say maximum happiness
we've reclassified Hispanics as white
wait
what like what I mean the Spanish are
technically your
in so short maybe I'll let that slide
too fucking that's fine all right no big
deal right no big deal
for maximum happiness we arrest 25% of
black males and then we'll call you
racist whoa hold on wait a second I
didn't arrest them well how am i
involved in this so now there's there's
contentions if you start you might start
to see a pattern here and it's like well
no because if you if you don't you're
one of these you'll be driven here so
you can't talk about the pattern and
because you can't talk about the pattern
we just gonna keep going
because we can let's keep going so now
by the way women now you have to work 12
hours a day
oh yeah and you go and it's called
freedom by the way so whoo good job so
now you get to work like slaves all day
awesome can't talk about it can't call
that pattern let's keep going we no
longer published m2 or m3 so we don't
even know our own money supply
derivatives post credit hmm we just is
for maximum happiness that's why we
stopped posting the velocity numbers
from the Federal Reserve we had to
maximize happiness you see well that
we're maximizing happiness some more we
decided to start a war last for 17 years
wait hold on how do we get B here from
there how do we get to this blurb from
all this stuff well it's simple
these blurbs didn't matter insofar as
they tested your ability to speak up and
you didn't speak up so now we can push
altra hard now we could push super hard
because we've already conceived already
setup the fact that if you recognize the
pattern we will slap you
and we'll just keep going we already got
the war going for 17 years let's push it
let's go to the next step to maximize
happiness we've decided that
unaccountable society-wide psychological
research is the new economy the whole
thing everything that Facebook and
Google does that's the new economy and
we're doing it for maximum happiness and
the only reason you can even get to this
part is cuz you allowed this part yeah
that already crashed we already figured
out that anybody who sees the pattern
here you know 9/11 coups all day long
every single one of these bubbles has
their own special brand of conspiracy
theorists that's just ready for you to
insult mother and her ass and go after
it's just hand delivered right to you
just waiting for you to use
I mean this I mean we've already gotten
to the level of absurdity here for right
so you know we're trying to maximize
happiness fuck it let's go all the way
let's see how how bad we can really make
it two plus two equals five now now for
some of you this might be the line this
might finally be it it wasn't though it
wasn't the large amount of wars in the
body count in the wealth destruction
everything else that wasn't it nope
wasn't your bagga-t this one might be
the one right this one you're finally
gonna stand up and say enough is enough
right no you're not because this entire
army of people have already lined up and
they're ready to slap you too and they
will
so the reality is that they're
maximizing happiness so they could do
whatever they want that's reality it has
nothing to do with maximizing happiness
because you've let these abuses slide
for so long that they can do whatever
they want now what do you look like in
this process may be a loyal freedom
fighter you're gonna fight the cars
manikin I'm not gonna do that because
why do you why are we selecting for the
right side of history right why we even
care about maximizing happiness most of
us live here to be honest no barring
some no physical ailment or or serious
problem we try to live here they tell us
to live here I mostly live here
something mostly live here on this line
we live here right so if this represents
all human potential this picture right
here if this represents all human
possibility and all the future that you
can have and all the things you intend
to do and your dreams and your hopes and
ambitions if you take this person and
you put them in this mess
you end up with this
you end up with a really well-trained
dog with that treat right there
an eyes of pure panic because it's
waiting for the command to snap the tree
and it's never going to get the command
all is its gonna get is more abuse
forever because we're maximizing
happiness that's what we've done and if
you disagree with any of these steps
along the way any one of these points
you come up with you were up against
this every single bubble along the way
every single one now this guy he's made
himself he's made peace of this fate he
knows he'll never be anything and that's
just the end of him but these people are
always at the ready just waiting to slap
you for not maximizing happiness and
then we get our morality machines the
functional AI which will be the morality
police for the blue church there already
are in fact so here's our little
morality machine we've gone over here's
our little blue line or blue plum line
here's our behavioral state machine as
we identify how to how to morph states
over time for ideal outcomes for on
behalf of this marauding machine so
perhaps this tree looks like we're
deploying chatbots to simulate
socialization so if a person is
deviating from the blue line we can
bring them back by giving them some
human interaction something where they
can say oh well I had a socialize today
you felt good
maybe we can induce lapped or epidemics
with memes and content sharing it all
around we could do that too we'll bring
you back to the blue line we're
maximizing happiness right then we can
activate deep dream conflict assets and
it can pump your adrenaline and dopamine
deep dream is a it's a Google project
designed to how do I put this
activate people into frothing beasts
it's probably the best way to describe
it so nobody sees somebody acting
hyper-partisan on the internet it's not
that that person's actually at fault
they've been activated by the
manipulations of these machines so
they've been actually induced into a
state of political rage because they
either need to put someone
closer to the blue line or they are
trying to burn them out so that they
that they capitulate can go back to the
blue line on their own and then fuck it
well just steer them towards opioids
we'll just show them advertising oh look
at oh god it's cass sunstein look at
this fucking clown so anyway this guy
he's a piece of work and he's gonna be
in a lot of trouble soon but he's part
of the nudge boys
yeah the nudge boys are a team of people
who believe in this crap right here
where they can control the option tree
and gradually nudge you towards that
blue line so that we don't have to
deploy like you know police with sticks
that look evil and mean and and deploy
soldiers that look evil and mean we can
just nudge you along the way and if we
can't you know we'll just you know they
just dive drug overdose whatever no big
deal so that's Cass Sunstein's big plan
there it is and he was that NSA doing
stuff about ten years ago but anyway
just hang tight you're gonna see more of
him soon so now I'd like to play a game
called connect the NPC to pornhub and
all the steps that you have to do to
make that happen right so once we once
we set up that that that morality
machine and we set up that blue line
reinforcement mechanism what we're
interested in what we're trying to do is
we're trying to happiness by itself
tends to imply choice so like I choose
out of all the odd like I'm at the
grocery store right so at this grocery
store and there's like bananas and
apples and what do I choose what am i
choosing right what maximizes my
happiness given this medley of choices
so I pick one it might not matter what I
pick but except it does matter to me for
my happiness so the happiness and choice
tend to be related but you can still get
happiness if it's done for reactive
safety so reactive safety means if
you're in a situation where all of your
choices are either burning barrels of
fire or an apple did you really choose
the Apple
no you won't the safest choice out of
all the mess it's available to you so
you can actually actually simulate
choice we can create the veneer of
choice but what you're actually doing is
you're you're getting reactive safety
because you're going to the safe to
Schaeffer's choice through the maze now
when you do this this actually allows
for unlimited violence and let me let me
show you how
so here's right here's our poor NPCs
options you can go to war he can deal
with a lynching or oh look a pretty girl
this someone has their mic on where you
pick a pretty girl did he pick the
pretty girl
did he really choose that or did he just
not want to go to war
did he really choose her did he just not
want to lynch someone you know I mean
was there choice what was the revelation
of preferences here so we've made our
choice now we got a bum and having the
shit kicked out of you now look another
Victoria model did I choose her
I didn't choose her I just didn't choose
this guy I didn't know I'm not making
choices here look at this burning
building and starving kidding some sex
kitten okay there bang
okay look connected the NPC to pornhub
we did it
did he make these choices he didn't make
those choices we just know what he
didn't pick what if you replaced this
low stuff he probably would have picked
that too but these were hurt his choices
so what you're doing is this is a
simulation of happiness this isn't real
happiness not by a long shot it's not
that this guy is a pervert who needs to
fucking you know crank it every couple
days or minutes or whatever this is a
guy
has no choice but to pick this because
the option tree is laid before him from
the morality machines and the blue line
reinforcement has forced him down this
road and as a result he's going down
this road of false happiness and
everything else is just collapsing
around him and there's nothing he's
going to do about it because he's
obviously not going to pick the mess so
he's allowing for unlimited violence and
he's telling himself he's happy
so now that he's established his happy
path through the mess and the noise any
threat to it becomes is equivalent to a
mortal threat because he doesn't want to
get dragged into that high conflict
scenario so he doesn't want to get
involved with this cuz you're always
racist forever and there's no cure
there's no there's nothing you just
raises forever that's it right so he
doesn't want to partake in that so he's
not going to the more debt you rack up
the more people they have to shoot
that's a losing game I don't have to
work to stay alive that's your job like
oh man that's really it's like nothing
you do matters everything you build will
burn these are things if he was forced
to address any of these it's just gonna
be like oh man he has no experience in
dealing with this stuff either there's
no point of reference you know then
there's you know the suffering of this
person's more important than yours so
now you're rationalizing why you should
dehumanize yourself and if you do speak
up well there's always this guy waiting
to pull me into the ground for not
speaking correctly at the right turn and
so what we've done is by creating by
optimizing for happiness by selecting
the maximum amount of happiness what
we've done is we've created a blue
church Pei Pig that's what we've done
we've created this dog in a human the
stack is right there all he has to do is
bite it but we won't let him it's right
there he's a pay Pig pay me you Pig or
this will happen to you so this isn't
happiness he's not selecting for
happiness but the blue church can tell
you that he is because we've optimized
for it and this is what it is this is
the Bentham prison this is the Bentham's
panopticon prison established to create
this self monitoring prisoner
so now that we know how the prison works
and we know the problems of selecting
for the blue line above all other things
and selecting for happiness how do we
undo it how do we reverse all that now
yeah we could approach this with a a
very structured philosophical view and
we could use Marxism and we can do
critical theory and we can do right side
of it yeah we could do more blue chart
shit sure yeah we could do that too a
blue in the face but what I'm doing is
is pointing out absurd logic and the
only way to beat logic is use something
that is absolutely not logical at all
and I'm gonna use alchemy because
there's no logic in alchemy because if
the people who are selecting for certain
types of logic this absurd logic system
that I've pointed out they have no skill
no no understanding of this stuff they
have no talent in it whatsoever and they
can't actually use it and fight against
it so what I'm gonna show you is how to
use alchemical comprehension a very
small snippet of it to reverse the
domestication of human beings now some
people would call this radicalizing
terrorists I call it temporarily
suspending domestication I intend for
people to go back to being domesticated
afterwards but this is how you do it
from an alchemical position a wolf pack
plus copper I'm pretty sure I just lost
you a wolf pack plus copper equals R Pei
Pig
the inverse is also true if I remove the
copper I get the Wolfpack back now what
the fuck does that mean right that all
right now I've already jump the ship of
logic but I told you I would I said I'm
not going to use logic I'm going to use
like semblances of it but I'm not gonna
use like this like structured thing
first you're probably stuck here right
you don't know what copper what I what I
mean copper like like I hit you in a
penny like I hit a wolf with a penny and
you know that's not what I'm saying
gotta understand the alchemy of copper
so this is a modern alchemical symbol
for copper but this is not the original
simple the original symbol for copper
ladies and gentlemen drumroll please is
this you've seen this symbol before
you've seen this symbol your entire
fucking life this is the symbol of the
feminine you're wrong it's not the
feminine it's actually copper
it was never feminine
copper as the feminine copper cables
laid all over the world everywhere
connecting you and me right now copper
in the circuit boards the computers that
are running all the processing for all
the image in the voice that you're
hearing for me right now
see copper was
this binding between Venus and copper
was intrinsic but Venus was never a
Roman god she was a Carthaginian god
in fact - an alchemist the Internet is
the leylines of Venus the whole internet
the entire goddamn internet is the
ley-line of Venus so when I say remove
the copper and you'll turn those pay
pigs back in the Wolves this is what I'm
talking about you remove the leylines of
Venus
so how does that look so we go back to
our blue our blue line formula our blue
line mechanism and we realize that
instead of selecting for any one of
these endlessly and mindlessly to create
happiness any one of these directions is
actually straight up dehumanization only
the feminine energy would pick this
because to them and to that energy in
particular I should say not the females
but did I energy maximizing happiness is
what you want to do that's exactly what
you want to do maybe a mother watching
over children a woman trying to piece
together a community that's been
destroyed by war trying to keep the
column between different people that's
typically what the blue church found
itself in but in reality and Bentham
told us that he was gonna make a pan
Opticon he fucking told us he was gonna
do that it was right there all of this
is dehumanization you go further in any
one of these just straight-up
dehumanization that's where you end up
let's just start with being alive let's
not talk about optimizing or trying to
create a better or anything let's just
just start with alive right where
there's pain and there's pleasure and
that's life let's just start there right
and then if you find that you're
drifting towards here everything syncing
issues you're trying to bring it back
you're not trying to eliminate pain
you're not trying to maximize pressure
pleasure you're trying to understand why
your model of the world isn't sinking so
much with what you think it should be
and you got to work that you need some
tools to help you figure that one out
and if you just say fuck and I don't
need the tools you just keep going
that's just straight applies you just
you know you care about you know
maximizing for any one of these things
that supposed to bring you back and then
that will always cascade in the
dehumanization until an opposing force
drags you back in and by the way this is
inverting by removing the leylines Venus
what we end up with is the
we end up with no longer selecting for
happiness we're actually selecting for
equilibrium instead now that that's
that's transitory it's not that Venus is
removed and thus everything's cure if
you remove the leylines of Venus
something is obviously going to take its
place but for enough time to actually
get our you know get our act together
and think about all the stuff that we've
been going through in the past 200 years
it's probably a good start to just get
rid of that copper completely and by the
way the inverse of copper was a less
antimony
which is actually known as the gray wolf
so that's how you that's how you end up
with that's how you use alchemy to get
to the scenario that I'm talking about
where you can undo the blue church line
you remove the copper and you end up
with the gray wolf you end up with the
wolf pack that has to constantly balance
itself out it has to stay alive it has
to synchronize with each of its own and
if any of them step in the bicep that
that community will pull you back in the
Wolves work together the Wolves work in
a pack when you were selecting for
maximization you were working as an
individual you were working alone of
course it's gonna maximize your
happiness because you don't have a pack
so remove the leylines
you get the gray wolf and that's it
thanks for listening alright so um if
you have any questions drop them in the
chat box for Pat and if you want me to
read on your behalf I will do so just to
indicate that so yeah that was um not
even where to begin with that maybe you
could like imagine some people watching
this and I think okay jump the shark
when you mentioned alchemy stuff could
you like I like a 101 and alchemy and
how you personally came across that in
your journey yes my usage of alchemy
isn't to be some warlock or some witch
moo-ha-ha with burning candles that's
not what I'm talking about
alchemy is a very old system of
epistemic very old so imagine once upon
a time that humans didn't have science
and so they don't have science so
therefore they can't make sense at the
universe that's not true you can't make
that statement they do make sense of the
universe and we know that because we
exist now they made sense they made
enough sense of the universe to breed us
into existence they did that without
science so therefore they had some
comprehension of epistemic stew get us
to this point the clean cut that's tried
that Newt that the blue church likes to
say and says oh everything is
superstitious except my blue line
science that's just them ashamed of
their point of origin
alchemy is how they got that science for
starters so the other reason I pick it
is because it is such a massive
thousands of years of epistemic s' if I
had an AI and I was trying to understand
human epistemic s' I wouldn't start with
now I wouldn't look at now and say oh
I'm gonna use now as a snapshot to
figure out the entire epistemic base of
the human condition you are working from
a poor poor standpoint there it's much
better to go back through history
thousands of years of alchemical
understandings because that's the
incompleteness of how the human brain
actually works how it makes jumps from
here to there without logic without
anything really it just does what it
does and finds the leap there's no you
can sit there and be like well you got
lucky once that's not reproducible thank
you autism professor professor great
that's that's not the point the point is
humans made sense of the world without
logic without science and alchemy embeds
that entire entire line of reasoning so
if I was an AI person trying to figure
out human knowledge and human cognition
I would throw science out the goddamn
window science has nothing to do with it
I would start with alchemy just to get
an understanding of that primordial
human brain how it was making sense of
the world so that that's why I pick
alchemy because the blue church has no
fucking idea how to deal with it and how
did you stumble on it
alchemy thread it was trying to do
something that was huge and I realized
my entire approach was wrong and so I
concluded that to get what I want I had
to steer civilization and the only way
to do that was through alchemy which is
particular and called soul alchemy which
I had to deal with which has no
relationship to blood alchemy which is
dumb shit don't do that stuff it's
stupid soul alchemy is the specific kind
that I picked
do you ever explain it like I'm five
version of sighs presentation selecting
for happiness will breed nothing but
unhappiness in order to fight the system
in which that happiness was built upon
you have to use the opposite of this you
have to use the opposite of the logic
that system was built upon you have to
use alchemy
what's the alchemy stuff so everything I
was just saying before before the chat
now still went over my head I see so
imagine a world where you had 200 words
so instead of the 20,000 words you know
now on average you only have 200 can you
describe the universe the answer is yes
you can
adding more words doesn't describe the
universe better it just describes it at
a better resolution it doesn't mean
there's parts of the universe you can't
conceive of all the stuff we're running
around today with or just rehashes of
the Grecians anyway from 2,000 years ago
and they didn't even have a telescope so
what is what is our reasoning capability
is it bits is it bytes is it science is
it math is it logic no it's none of
those things that is derivative of the
human cognition derivative of human
experience so if you want to start with
how we got to science you have to start
with where we started with which was our
chemical understanding incomplete
knowledge dark fragmented artisanal
guilds of knowledge and information
that's how we got started on knowledge
so alchemy is a is a ecosystem of
attempts it's like proto epistemology
it's probably easiest way to describing
so 10 generals lost asked about explain
it like I'm five about the copper thing
and Andrea also had a related question
which was I was hoping to follow up on
what if you can reactivate the copper
but Andrew maybe you can go off mute and
ask your question to Pat okay my video
on um what are some like practical like
examples of what it would mean to remove
the copper like what's like a practical
everyday
yeah what's what like what's practical
everyday examples of removing the copper
of like not maximizing happiness sure so
a very simple trick you would do is
whether any action you you would start
with picking a random action not even
every action that's too much discipline
pick a random one like one a day or
whatever you're about to do something
and you'd stop yourself and you say you
know you do the do the the net flow
does this bring joy right that all that
old meme that was floating around for a
while but instead of asking that quest
that question but instead of using it as
a filter to say okay well I'm going to
keep doing this or I'm going to throw
stuff out if it does bring you joy don't
do it
just don't do it and the reason you do
that is to start training your brain and
to understand reality from a different
perspective
not necessarily to end up like Diogenes
on the street with you know no clothes
and dirt and stuff like that but to deny
yourself on your own terms
pleasure will give you access to parts
your brain you never thought possible
you have to keep doing it though it's
not obvious and it's not easy because
most of us are trained to if people are
coming after our ability to maximize
pressure we are trained with every
manner of fight in us to prevent that
from happening we can go to the state we
can go to the we can go to social media
we can do all these things and say oh
I'm gonna get you you stop my happiness
how dare you I'm tell Dad but in reality
the only one who can stop you from
pursuing happiness is yourself and if
you don't know how to do that
it's a good skill to learn and so I'd
start there for a daily practical stuff
it's small stuff but it builds up over
time okay there's a question to wait on
someone's behalf Patrick give you copper
removal as imminent and if so how do you
feel about Kipling's law of the jungle
law of the law of the jungle is that's a
rehash of Hobbes Leviathan so it's it's
kind of the idea that someone has to
maximize the happiness because if
everybody's maximizing their happiness
then it's a mess but it's even a mess
even if it is just one person maximizing
happiness maximizing the happiness is
what causes the messes so I mean there's
there's many of many arguments that is
used to ultimately justify the existence
of that blue line but in terms of
removing the copper that's a lot of what
my a I warfare is focused on removing
the actual means of transmission of this
weaponized happiness and and just making
sure that the copper does not have the
Femina the unchecked feminised energy
that is currently saturated with
patches O'Malley you had a question yeah
so it seems like the the tree on the
dog's nose is analogous to the
transcendent identity or like authentic
mode of being one that would produce
meaning that would inoculate the
individual from the system like this
this blue Turk system it seemed like
that the treat on its nose it seemed
like it's always waiting there for us to
embrace it but it would require
embracing pain for something that's much
more important than happiness and if
suffering is de facto bad then you can't
then stretching your belief systems is
bad and doesn't take place so
essentially you're saying getting people
to believe and act out the notion that
they're more than their identity is what
we humanize is that that's right you are
more than your identity because as in
the in the previous episode we go very
deeply into identity and heuristics of
it and how that becomes control systems
and that type of stuff so the treat is
exactly as it's pretty close to it might
be identical to what you're describing
there the idea that hey you don't have
to keep playing this game if you don't
want to you can leave it anytime you
just have to normal you don't have a
normalize yourself to pain and invite
abuse that's some blue church thinking
bullshit where if you're allowed oh I
took pain once and so now therefore
there's an a million abusers around me
come on give me a break that's not a
mature relationship with you know your
own goddamn existence pain happens it's
real there's all shit's things dying on
your body all the time my skin cells are
dying every 7 seconds there's all kinds
of death happening around me it's if
this is part of being here we didn't
have a choice we're kind of born here we
it's we just along for the ride for the
most part so being pain is okay it's
okay like it's okay to say you don't
need pleasure all the goddamn time like
that shouldn't be too radical of an ass
but for most people at this so it's a
really clever way of tricking people
into enslaving themselves and like just
by denying parts of reality I also think
that the theological allegories to this
are like suspicious and coincidental
yeah I mean that's
it's definitely that to be said but it's
one of the more ideal control mechanisms
for populations because it's insidious
and because it gets buy-in so early on
and you could just keep doing it as long
as you put the veneer of happiness up
all times for the maximum happiness bla
bla bla we've already seen what that
looks like
Lucas you had a question hey I was just
wondering both the overlaps of alchemy
and cybernetics theory because as I was
going through my development I was more
into the esoteric mystery traditions and
then when I went over into cybernetic
theory I know it's a lot of parallels I
just want to know if you saw a lot of
parallels and if you did where do you
think they they were yes the other
reason I picked alchemy I mean just to
reiterate and reassert I'm not picking
alchemy for moo-ha-ha mystical points
it's not like I'm approaching this from
a material human material humanist
perspective so the reason I another
reason I picked alchemy in addition to
it being a massive collection of
unexplored epistemology that you can you
know do some good research on especially
in pre science what human cognition is
capable of which is the inverse of today
because there's only a handful of
variations of human cognition that are
allowed to be present the other benefit
of alchemy is that it exclusively sees
the world as black boxes exclusively so
I poke this thing I don't know what that
thing is I may never know what that
thing is but it produced an output so I
poke the jellyfish and it moved away and
it stung me okay I have a rough idea of
what that black box now is I never turn
around and try to get it'll open the
damn thing and see what's going on in
the black box
alchemy gets you comfortable with the
idea that you'll never know and you
don't need to know there's no point in
that but you need to know is that you
poke it you get the output and that's
what cybernetics is - cybernetics is the
study of saying I what is a population
right what what is a hundred million
people do I poke a hundred million
people do I need to open up every person
to figure out a pond no you don't need
to do any of that stuff so you poke you
treat the population as a black box you
poke it out you go the same things true
of neural networks unexplained neural
networks are identical to the process
I'm talking about where I send its input
it does its categorizations it finds the
correlations and it has its output I
don't actually know what those hidden
layers are called it's literally called
hidden layers so I can't even know so
how come he gets you comfortable with
the idea that you don't need
as opposed to science which says I need
infinite data at all times I don't care
how many data centers I have to build
every five seconds and that's just
absurd that's an absurd unsustainable
proposition when it comes to
epistemology so alchemy is a much better
suited well thank you yeah I appreciate
it so here's a question I read on
someone's behalf
what would a wolf society look like is
it like one Vulcans drop emotions and
switch to logic no emotions that's how
they work well so that's how they work
so well together they use their emotions
their emotions are actually functional
as opposed to being vanity the emotions
we have are are purely for pleasure
these days I have an emotion it's it's D
hinge its unhinged from social
consequence for the most part it's not
tied to my existence I just happen to
have emotions it sounds like punishment
if you ask me emotions not serving a
function where they just happen to exist
and it interferes with my ability to get
high that sounds terrible that's
absolutely that's punishment
I don't want emotions in that context
but the reality is we we're tribal
creatures
that's a taboo that's a pattern
recognizing taboo to call that out but
we're we're tribal creatures those
emotions were designed for our survival
so those emotions need to be rooted in
the tribal context for them to make
sense so it's not that there's wolves
running around killing everybody emotion
heartless monsters that's if you're
looking at the world from the blue
church maximizing pleasure perspective I
don't I don't go into like a federal
reserve of wild land and say oh that
there's those mountain lions are
murderers killing two caribou I mean oh
man that's that's the relationship
that's the balance that makes all that
possible so you know stop stop trying to
find pleasure and every goddamn thing
because if you do you're gonna be
sitting there like criticizing mountain
lions who the fuck does that Daniel II
get a question about mm-hmm
had to do how how can he sort of
cultivate agency and try to steer away
from learned helplessness which is
something that you know blue church
psyops try to do yeah I mean learn
helplessness is is an essential part of
returning people to the blue line in
terms of agency agency is a tough one
because there's the implication that I
ran daeun conclusion that I am myself
and I am all that is maybe that's true I
don't know I don't think that's true I
think there is a meta individual for
every individual I think we live in side
the minds and the experiences of other
people too I think we're always there no
matter what with or without our
permission so it's not necessarily to be
mindful and be paralysed by that
analysis although we do have the
cognitive equipment to make that
analysis and that's what a lot of our
brain was about to do but the idea of
achieving agency in a sea of chaos that
can push us at its whim whenever at once
that is something definitely worth
exploring in greater depth I don't know
if the alchemists had about chemists had
concepts of agency like that because
again that would violate the blackbox
principle you would have to what you
would be doing is you'd be redirecting
your outputs back to your own inputs and
that's not necessarily self referential
but it's your attempt to explore your
own brain which just has always resulted
in total failures there's there's a
whole body of there's a whole network of
people who have fucked that up royally
redirecting their outputs their own
inputs to examine their own mind and
that can be introspection to a degree
but if you follow the blue church you
start cracking open your own brain
trying to find neurons here and there
and you keep calling it progress no
matter how many times it fucks up or
gets it wrong so agency probably has to
be put in check to a degree as well and
that can that can be made done that can
be done so by social accountability your
actions are held
they are because you live in the minds
of other people as well you are
accountable for what goes on and that
social network that you are accountable
to can prevent you from engaging in that
runaway agency if that makes sense
all right Raven you had a few questions
and there's one that was voted popular
but I'm not gonna pick that one because
I have my own interests so I was
wondering about the implications of this
trajectory of thought for virtual
reality so in virtual reality some of
the initial pieces of media that were
made that were really popularized were
of like Syrian refugee camps for example
that were really about kind of exposing
an individual to the perspective of
another to invoke empathy what do you
think about the ability for the blue
church to leverage virtual reality for
kind of its own ends they will that is
when it comes to blue church every
options on the table at all times
because they only know one play and that
is to maximize happiness by any means
necessary
so yes VR is definitely leveraged in
that regard but at the same time the
thing about empathy is that if it's
misplaced it also breeds resentment
it's got to be real careful with that
did you want to ask you
the question reason sure I'll ask well I
think I'm curious about so you have this
lineage of thought that you've kind of
laid out in this presentation are there
philosophers or people who resisted that
path of logic who you see as being kind
of understudied that you think maybe we
should look into who are some of them
yeah there are a lot of the black box
philosophers were terminated from
history it's hard to find most of them
were in the Bronze Age the only way I
can actually gleam them is by kind of
looking at the psycho history of the
time meaning I tried to look at why
we're cults so prevalent in the Bronze
Age why were religions seen as where the
gods walked amongst them why is that why
is that which is so normal back then so
alien to us now I have to do
differential analysis to find those
points of interesting nexuses that
appear when you start looking at that
and start answering some of those
questions in terms of people who really
got it right the Gnostics come to mind
immediately they the post Judean
Gnostics in particular they lineage of
Simon they the Romans just brutalized
them these were God's chosen people and
then the Romans just completely trashed
the everliving shit out of them it's
what they banned him from the Roman
Empire put a bounty on every Jewish head
and effectively caused the Diaspora when
you're trying to make sense of how if
you were a chosen people why this
happened to you you and you come up with
some pretty interesting psychological
conclusions about how to separate self
from reality and divine from reality at
the same time so they they had a they're
probably good entry level stuff to look
into if you keep that psychological I'm
sorry if you keep that historical fact
in mind that the Gnostics did not appear
in a vacuum and that they did appear as
a result of the Roman destruction of
Judea and once you keep that in in
perspective then you start to see oh
okay this is what they're doing
actually actually using the separation
of reality in theology there almost
weaponized it to a degree and we saw
that with when the Romans finally bent
the knee and adopted Christianity not a
thing about Christianity is that the
Romans didn't see Christians they
thought there are all Jewish subverts if
they saw they saw Christ as just another
Jewish radical and so they weren't
actually killing Christians in their
eyes they were they were killing Jews so
there's there's that whole part of it
but there's a lot of that period of
history where if you keep those
geopolitical events in mind you start to
see glimpses of this black box
rationalization of things that they
can't even begin to possibly measure
with any degree of certainty not the way
that VCS and and academics and the state
runs their procurement stuff now
[Music]
I'm a keeper you had a question
yeah hey Pat I like the talk I wanted to
ask about the contrast between the
pursuit of scientific understanding
versus the pursuit of pleasure because I
do believe there's a strain of serious
scientists who value intellectual
understanding over in and pleasure but
you explained they're a dying breed
because they're incentivized to be eaten
this um I kind of think part of the
dying the reason they're dying breed is
also that they they fail to find a
proper like intellectual basis for
certain problems like they couldn't
bridge the is op divide so do you think
there could be a new philosophy or
metaphysics to resolve this problem and
is that what you're doing yes that is
exactly what I'm doing because this is
how I was trying to solve the problem
that I couldn't solve before the idea
was to trick an AI into solving it for
me and so I think that my approach is
something that more people should be
doing not just because I want the ego
trip I don't I'll probably disappear
into the woods somewhere but I think
it's useful to consider that we are
about to walk into a world where we have
multipolar cognitions it's not just a
monopoly on cognition that the human
mind has had for five thousand years
we're gonna have a eyes of various
capacity and neuro chimera and all kinds
of genetic horror shows that are just on
display at all times and they're going
to be solving problems that we can't
even see
that's gonna be wild like you're gonna
have this like this ant bat slug banana
brain bananas on that branch but they're
gonna be solving problems that we're
gonna be like the fuckin like n
dimensional things we can't even
comprehend so how do you make not even
make sense of this world at that point
making sense it's the last thing you
want to do because you'll be too busy
focusing all your resources on making
sense you won't even be able to survive
it so you're probably better off just
embracing the idea that this is a
possibility and you may have to go a
little black box for a while just to get
your footing and it's okay we have the
neural equipment to do that but in terms
of blue chairs scientists eventually you
know always siding with public policy
and as a result always siding with blue
line maximization of happiness
they are already fighting AI right now
they're demanding explainable AI well
you need to explain your stuff in
scientific terms but man these damn AI
is right now they they find correlation
of the weirdest stuff stuff that you
would never have even seen as useful so
they're still approaching this from a
scientific methodology where you where
you create this white paper that's
defensible for all of time when in
reality you just need the correlation
for that moment in time you just need a
correlation for that for that for those
60 days and then you throw it aside and
then a new correlation comes in and you
need that for three days and you toss it
aside and then a new correlation comes
in you're not trying to find the
fundamental axiom that you can then
extrapolate not trying to find the plumb
line and then defend it for all of time
you're trying to find the stints the
cognitive stints that allow you to
continue to move forward in an adaptive
space where you have lost the monopoly
on cognition and if they don't want to
play that game and they dig their heels
and I got 6,000 and of all brains
they're coming so fuck you that's it
interesting very interesting
there's another one passes near fuck
brain cyclist that shit all day okay
topi had a clarification question yeah
sure so I was just wondering if I got
essence right so pain of transformation
has been weaponized by the humanistic
hedonism for suppression and the cure is
a no chemical process both because it is
transformation and copper is the
inhibiting factor in the fact that the
blue church has no idea how to make
sense about coming yeah sure yes so the
copper as a symbol as a ley line for
Venus the feminine energy being
everywhere at all times and we are just
swimming in it at all times
that is a alchemical description that if
you bring it to actual alchemists and
people who study this stuff they'll be
like oh well I didn't think about it
like that right so now it's just like
poof now they can work with that in
their own logic in their own context
that's a logic and context step by the
way the blue church doesn't even can't
even begin to penetrate or understand so
these people will come up with solutions
and I know this because in the Bronze
Age people with identical ways of
thinking still came up with solutions
that worked I know this because history
is a thing so I don't need to sit there
and defend white papers all day it's
stupid I know that it works I can hand
us off to people who do think like this
and they'll find solutions that will
justify a reason meanwhile they actually
get results so yeah that's that's the
benefits of alchemy there to fight that
blue line maximization okay this might
be our last question
key and bring us home yeah I'm feeling a
lot of nervousness so I'm just taking a
cue from Peter it's check-ins but the
question the question is about into
antimony of the the alchemy of that
because you mentioned the you mentioned
the word equilibrium and so I'm just
trying to understand this the last
couple slides of those symbols
the e plus and minus and also saying
it's really funny to see two plus two
equals five yep that's my question I
think I I think I I think I understand
the alchemy so everyone here is
currently confused by a lot of the
alchemy stuff
and that's my point that's exactly my
point
you can't make sense of it you can't
figure it out
you can't apply your logic and your
science and your reason and your
intellectual and your experiences and
everything you've been trained to do you
can't figure it out so if I came up with
attacks using that vector
there ain't fuck all you can do about it
cuz you don't even know where to start
so the confusion you're having now yes
that's the goal that's the purpose it's
hiding the attack vector in absurdity
and hiding it in things that you're not
trained to understand and train to
dismiss so as a result I have free
attack advantage while you're just like
I don't get it so that's why I was stats
is why I'm selecting for alchemy in this
example to show you that even from
absurdity I can still attack the blue
church
but I think the question I mean like I
just wanted to know a little bit of more
about antimony but also it's reminding
me about a series that I haven't read
yet by Brandon Sanderson I think um do
you have a familiarity with that I do
not have regarding intima antimony it's
um the antimony is it it is an
interesting inversion of copper
now how copper and Venus got bound
together that was I think I was Roman
Roman times you can look that one up I
don't I don't have that one off the top
of my head but I found it very
interesting that that the inverse of
Venus was actually the Great Wolf I
found that to be like oh wow okay sorry
I it's it's this is a hard one this is a
hard talk no no the attack is hilarious
and fun and now I get to really think
through these things that's what's great
so thank you oh cool so we'll end it
there Pat you have any final final
thoughts for us so yes as you're
watching the season you're starting to
see that there is no amount of
creativity and skill that can be
deployed to really really bring pain to
the blue church for all the monstrous
things they have been doing for the past
hundred and fifty years I will use
science we use not science how we use
absurdity I will use clowns and cars
with pigeons and seagulls whatever the
hell I can come up with I'm going to
explain to you guys how to do it as well
and that's just what total epistemic war
looks like so that's what you need to do
and to get these people to heal because
they won't come to heal because for the
pursuit of pleasure they're gonna do
whatever they want
all right buckle up everyone so how many
episodes of this season someone in this
um when I saw the chatbox
exploring the mean probably has two or
three left and then there's some what's
next week it's gonna be though don't
know yet cool all right well thank you
pat thank you everyone for your
questions
yeah upcoming events tomorrow we have
let's see we have Daniels uh because
engines the metagame mastermind that's
at 6 p.m. Eastern Time and I think
Daniel is going to be back next week
back to emceeing and then we have a few
cool events coming up Jonathan
pachow talking about the symbolic world
that's on whatever June 29th is Monday
at 3 p.m. Eastern Time so you can check
out that our Sippy in the website and
the stoah is based off a gift economy if
you're inspired to give a gift directly
to Pat himself if you so choose you can
just go to the store that's see a slash
gift alright everyone thank you so much